

# BIRTHDATE -----

28/07/1992

# NATIONALITY

Italian

#### CONTACTS

andreagulino@me.com

+39-3451462332

#### PROGRAMMING SKILLS -----

JAVATYPESCRIPTCI/CDAWSDYNAMODBλCLOUDFORMATION NEXTJSMONITORINGANALYTICSBIG DATAAPACHE SPARKPYTHONSCALAGIT

# WAYS OF WORKING

AGILE LeSS TDD

WEBSITE

andreagulino.github.io

# **ANDREA GULINO**

PHD IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

# Summary -----

I am a PhD in Information Technology, specialized in the design of scalable systems and algorithms for data-intensive applications.

Since March 2021 I have been working as a software engineer on the re-design and development of a WW **E-commerce** platform along with the integration of new payment systems.

# Work Experience

#### **GUCCI**

#### **Digital Product Developer**

2021-present

- New omni-channel e-commerce platform design and full-stack development / Migration from legacy system
- Integration of new payment systems (express payments, instalments)

#### Politecnico di Milano

2018-2019

#### **Teaching Assistant**

Basic and advanced programming classes for engineering students

# Education -----

#### Politecnico di Milano

2017-2020	PhD cum laude in Information Technology
2014-2017	Master's Degree in Computer Science and Engineering
2011-2014	Bachelor's Degree - Ingegneria Informatica

#### Tongji University 同济大学 - Shanghai

2012-2013 Double degree exchange program (1 year)

### Research

#### **Research Areas**

Cloud Computing, System Architectures, Distributed Algorithms, Databases, Computational Genomics.

#### **Oral Presentations**

2018 IEEE Big Data (Seattle), 2019 IEEE BIBM (San Diego), 2020 IEEE MASCOTS (Nice).

#### **Publications**

14 publications, 7 as a first author. More details are available on my personal website and on <u>Google Scholar</u>.

#### **Collaborations**

Oxford University, Banca D'Italia.